Finding Aid for Michigan State Grange Records, 1873-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan State Grange Records 1873-2005
Michigan State Grange.
1 reel of microfilm
1 oversize folder
5 oversize volumes
55.5 linear feet
851992 Bg 2; BG; UBGm
Minutes of executive committee, 1874-2002 (with some gaps); minutes and proceedings of state convention, 1873-1880; financial records; and roster, 1873-1978, of lodges chartered by Michigan Grange, showing date of charter, location and other data; also records of various defunct local granges.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were deposited by the Michigan State Grange (donor no. 3903 ) beginning in 1962. The records of defunct locals came to the library in 2003-09.
The record group is open to research.
The Michigan State Grange was formally organized on April 15, 1873 at the Court House in the Village of Kalamazoo. The formation united the twenty local Granges that had already been established in 1872. The first local grange organized was Burnside Grange #1 on January 10, 1872 in Lapeer County. The Michigan Grange held its first Annual Session in Kalamazoo on January 21-23, 1874.
Members of the Grange "provide service to agriculture and rural areas on a variety of issues, including economic development, education, family endeavors, and legislation designed to assure a strong and viable Rural America." The members create and publish a list of issues of concern each year. "Major objectives of the National Grange support stewardship of America's natural resources; promotion of world-wide free trade; a combination of local and federal support for rural education, medical, communications, and road systems; non-partisan political participation; assurance of safe and properly labeled food products; organization of cooperatives and other economic services to support rural Americans; and elimination of direct government farm programs so as to assure a competitive and efficient farm system."
____________
This historical sketch was edited from the finding aid to the Michigan State Grange records housed at Michigan State University.
The records of the Michigan State Grange include minutes and proceedings of the state convention, minutes of the executive committee, financial statements; and rosters and applications for membership of individual chapters of the State Grange. Whenever a local chapter ceased operations, its records would be transferred to the State Grange office. The records of some of these defunct chapters make up the bulk of the State Grange record group. Records of local Granges may include minutes of lodge meetings, financial records and membership lists. The local records are listed in the contents list in the order in which they were received they were received from the state office. Two indexes, one by chapter name and the other by chapter number, should be used to locate the records of a particular chapter. The chapter numbers were assigned consecutively as the chapters were organized. Counties represented in these defunct chapters include Alcona, Antrim, Arenac, Charlevoix, Cheboygan, Chippewa, Crawford, Emmet, Genesee, Gogebic Hillsdale, Iosco, Jackson, Lenawee, Macomb, Marquette, Menominee, Midland, Monroe, Montmorency, Oscoda, Otsego, Sanilac, Saginaw, Schoolcraft, Shiawassee, Tuscola, Washtenaw, and Wayne.
Another portion of the record group includes materials of W. J. Brake, who was a lecturer for the National Grange and who held office for the State Grange.
Other records of the Michigan State Grange were donated to the University Archives and Historical Collections of Michigan State University. The MSU Archives holds the Grange records from the following counties: Allegan, Barry, Benzie, Berrien, Branch, Calhoun, Cass, Clare, Clinton, Eaton, Grand Traverse, Gratiot, Ingham, Ionia, Isabella, Kalamazoo, Kalkaska, Kent, Leelanau, Manistee, Mason, Mecosta, Montcalm, Muskegon, Newaygo, Oceana, Osceola, Otsego, Ottawa, Shiawassee, St. Joseph, Van Buren, and Wexford.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Michigan.; Farm life--Michigan.; Michigan State Grange.; Adrian Grange, No. 213 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Alba Bramble Grange, No. 1801 (Antrim County, Mich.); Ann Arbor Grange, No. 1566 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Antrim County Pomona Grange, No. 38 (Antrim County, Mich.); Austin Grange, No. 1331 (Hillsdale County, Mich.); Ash Center Grange, No. 471 (Monroe County, Mich.); Bay Grange, No. 597 (Arenac County, Mich.); Bear Creek Grange, No. 1266 (Emmet County, Mich.); Belleville Grange, No. 331 (Wayne County, Mich.); Bennington Grange, No. 873 (Shiawassee County, Mich.); Birthday Grange, No. 1352 (Schoolcraft County, Mich.); Boise Grange, No. 1181 (Midland County, Mich.); Bruce Armada Grange, No. 657 (Macomb County, Mich.); Burton Center Grange, No. 1072 (Genesee County, Mich.); Cambria Grange, No. 74 (Hillsdale County, Mich.); Coleman Grange, No. 1226 (Midland County, Mich.); Crawford Grange, No. 934 (Crawford County, Mich.); Cusic Lake Grange, No. 1728 (Macomb County, Mich.); Davis Grange, No. 1199 (Macomb County, Mich.); Davison Grange, No. 1285 (Genesee County, Mich.); Devereaux Grange, No. 45 (Jackson County, Mich.); Donaldson-Rosedale Grange, No. 1160 (Chippewa County, Mich.); East Almer Grange, No. 1701 (Tuscola County, Mich.); Ellington Grange, No. 1650 (Tuscola County, Mich.); Elmira Grange, No. 1863 (Antrim County, Mich.); Faith Grange, No. 594 (Sanilac County, Mich.); Fenton Grange, No. 1839 (Genesee County, Mich.); Fisher Grange, No. 790 (Alcona County, Mich.); Forest Grange, No. 823 (Saginaw County, Mich.); Forest Lawn, No. 1720 (Tuscola County, Mich.); Four Towns Grange, No. 745 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Fruit Ridge Grange, No. 276 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Gaines Grange (Genesee County, Mich.); Genesee County Pomona Grange, No. 48 (Genesee County, Mich.); Geneva Grange, No. 1227 (Midland County, Mich.); Goodrich Grange, No. 887 (Genesee County, Mich.); Grant-Eckland Grange, No. 1724 (Tuscola County, Mich.); Grass Lake Grange, No. 925 (Antrim County, Mich.); Harbor Springs Grange, No. 730 (Emmet County, Mich.); Hayes Grange, No. 871 (Otsego County, Mich.); Iosco County Pomona Grange, No. 89 (Iosco County, Mich.); Ironwood Grange, No. 1800 (Gogebic County, Mich.); Jackson County Pomona Grange, No. 79 (Jackson County, Mich.); Lafayette Grange, No. 92 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Lakefield Grange, No.1764 (Saginaw County, Mich.); Lakeview Grange, No. 872 (Otsego County, Mich.); Lakeview Juvenile Grange, No. 148 (Otsego County, Mich.); Lapeer Grange, No. 246 (Lapeer County, Mich.); Lickly Corners Grange, No. 274 (Ransom, Mich.: Township); Little River Grange, No. 1855 (Menominee County, Mich.); Macomb County Pomona Grange, No. 32 (Macomb County, Mich.); Maple Grove Grange, No. 1255 (Charlevoix County, Mich.); Maple Hill Grange, No. 691 (Antrim County, Mich.); Maple River Grange, No. 1437 (Emmet County, Mich.); Marion Center Grange, No. 956 (Charlevoix County, Mich.); Marquette County Pomona Grange, No. 77 (Marquette County, Mich.); Medina Grange, No. 277 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Millington Grange, No. 755 (Tuscola County, Mich.); North Sylvan Grange, No. 1460 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); North Rome Grange, No. 735 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Onsted Grange, No. 279 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Pioneer Grange, No. 811 (Oscoda County, Mich.); Pittsfield Union Grange, No. 882 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Ponto Grange, No. 1262 (Saginaw County, Mich.); Resort Grange, No. 841 (Emmet County, Mich.); Riverside Grange, No. 741 (Cheboygan County, Mich.); Rock Elm Grange, No. 705 (Charlevoix County, Mich.); Rollin Grange, No. 1814 (Manitou Beach, Mich.); Rose Township Grange, No. 1826 (Oakland County, Mich.); Rudyard Grange, No. 1824 (Chippewa County, Mich.); Saginaw Grange, No. 770 (Saginaw County, Mich.); Saline Grange, No. 1831 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Scio Grange, No. 329 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Skandia Grange, No. 1410 (Marquette County, Mich.); South Arm Grange, No. 815 (Charlevoix County, Mich.); South Dover Grange, No. 720 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Studley Junior Grange, No. 321 (Midland County, Mich.); Tipton Grange, No. 165 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Twin Lakes Grange, No. 1811 (Montmorency County, Mich.); Unionville Grange, No. 1636 (Tuscola County, Mich.); Washtenaw-Wayne Pomona Grange, No. 7 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Webster Grange, No. 111 (Washtenaw County, Mich.); Weston Grange, No. 276 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Wheatland Grange, No. 273 (Hillsdale County, Mich.); Woodstock Grange, No. 438 (Lenawee County, Mich.); Alcona County (Mich.); Antrim County (Mich.); Arenac County (Mich.); Crawford County (Mich.); Charlevoix County (Mich.); Cheboygan County (Mich.); Chippewa County (Mich.); Emmet County (Mich.); Genesee County (Mich.); Gogebic County (Mich.); Hillsdale County (Mich.); Iosco County (Mich.); Jackson County (Mich.); Lapeer County (Mich.); Lenawee County (Mich.); Macomb County (Mich.); Manitou Beach (Mich.); Marquette County (Mich.); Midland County (Mich.); Monroe County (Mich.); Montmorency County (Mich.); Oscoda County (Mich.); Otsego County (Mich.); Menominee County (Mich.); Monroe County (Mich.); Ransom (Mich.: Township); Saginaw County (Mich.); Sanilac County (Mich.); Schoolcraft County (Mich.); Shiawassee County (Mich.); Tuscola County (Mich.); Washtenaw County (Mich.); Wayne County (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Administrative Records
  - Proceedings of annual sessions 1873-1880 (Volume 1)
  - Executive Committee record books
    - 1874-1875 (Box 1)
    - 1875-1880 (Box 1)
    - 1881-1890 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee minute book 1874-1907 (Box 1)
    (Minute book for 1908-1922 missing)
  - Executive Committee minute book December 9, 1924-July 24, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee minute book December 1935-December 1938 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee minute book 1933-1935, 1942-1956 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee minutes 1951-1955 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee record books
    (includes minutes and financial statements)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 1)
      (includes financial statements from 1947)
    - 1954-1969 (Box 2)
    - 1966-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1972-1977 (Box 2)
    - 1974-1979 (Box 2)
    - 1977-1980 (Box 2)
    - 1979-1982 (Box 2)
    - 1983-1987 (Box 47)
    - 1988-1992 (Box 47)
    - 1992-1996 (Box 47)
    - 1997-2000 (Box 48)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 48)
  - Executive Committee record book 1991-2001, 2 expandable folders (Box 48)
    (probably maintained by Master Roland Winter)
  - Executive Committee records 1981-1985, 1987-1991, 8 folders (Box 43)
    (probably duplicate of bound record volumes)
  - "Fifth and Sixth" degree record book 1890-1906 (Box 43)
  - "Discussion topics and general information prepared for 1955 Grange District Meetings (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous papers, various dates (Box 43)
- Summary Information
  - Granges by counties, numbers and names (Box 43)
  - Active subordinates and active pomonas as of May 18, 1982, 1 folder; 1 volume (Box 43)
  - Michigan Grange List compiled by Roland G. Winter 2005 (Box 43)
    (arranged by number and by name)
  - Granges dropped from records from 1911-1941 (Box 43)
- Rosters, chapter applications
  - Roster of lodges chartered by Michigan Grange 1873-1978 (Volume 2)
    (also available is microfilm copy dated to 1961)
  - Chapter application and reorganized applications (Box 36)
    (arranged by chapter no.)
  - Chapter applications (miscellaneous), 4 folders (Box 44)
- Defunct Chapter Records
  - Tipton Grange #165 (Lenawee County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1873-1991 (Box 3)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1873-1991 (Box 4)
      (continued)
  - Pioneer Grange #811 (Oscoda County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1900-1980 (Box 5)
      (include scrapbooks containing clippings and photographs of facilities and activities from the 1950s)
  - Onsted Grange #279 (Lenawee County)
    (formerly Springville Grange)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1874-1983 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1874-1983 (Box 7)
  - Little River Grange #1855 (Menominee County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1940-1995 (Box 8)
      (include some records of Menominee County Pomona)
  - Rollin Grange #1814 (Manitou Beach, Lenawee County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1940-1994 (Box 9)
  - North Rome Grange #735 (Lenawee County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1904-1969 (Box 10)
  - Fisher Grange #790 (Alcona County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1943-1980 (Box 10)
  - Genesee Pomona Grange #48
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1915-1978 (Box 11)
  - Fenton Grange #1839 (Genesee County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1938-1985 (Box 12)
      (includes records of juvenile grange club)
  - Adrian Grange #213 (Lenawee County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1901-1990 (Box 13)
      see also oversize scrapbooks compiled by Grace Taylor; oversize vols. nos. 3,4,5
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1901-1990 (Box 14)
  - Lickly Corners Grange #274 (Ransom Township, Hillsdale County)
    - Minutes 1874-1976 (Box 15)
    - Minutes 1976-2003 (Box 16)
    - Treasurer's records, membership materials 1874-2000 (Box 16)
      (include Juvenile Grange #63)
  - Bruce Armada Grange #657 (Macomb County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1918-1984 (Box 17)
      (include scattered photographs)
  - Gaines Grange (Genesee County)
    - Secretary's book 1937-1942 and treasurer's record book, 1939-1943 (Box 17)
  - Jackson County Pomona Grange #79
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1922-1987 (Box 18)
  - Antrim County Pomona Grange #38
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1896-1963 (Box 18)
  - Elmira Grange #1863 (Antrim County)
    - Secretary's record book 1941-1957 (Box 18)
  - Riverside Grange #741 (Cheboygan County)
    - Secretary's record books 1909-1913, 1956-1963 (Box 19)
  - Rudyard Grange #1824 (Chippewa County)
    - Secretary's minute books 1947-1951, 1955-1960 (Box 19)
  - Twin Lakes Grange #1811 (Montmorency County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1936-1948 (Box 19)
  - Donaldson-Rosedale Grange #1160 (Chippewa County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1933-1975 (Box 19)
  - Wheatland Grange #273 (Hillsdale County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1874-1990 (Box 20)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1874-1990 (Box 21)
  - Belleville Grange #331 (Wayne County)
    - Secretary's record books 1878-1888, 1927-1954 (Box 22)
  - Cusic Lake Grange #1728 (Macomb County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1927-1967 (Box 22)
  - Davis Grange #1199 (Macomb County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1904-1982 (Box 22)
  - Alba Bramble Grange #1801
    - Minutes, etc. 1940-1953 (Box 22)
  - Bay Grange #597 (Arenac County)
    - Secretary's record book 1957-1963 (Box 22)
  - Grass Lake Grange #925 (Antrim County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1901-1954 (Box 23)
  - Maple River Grange #1437 (Emmet County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1910-1979 (Box 24)
  - Boise Grange #1181 (Midland County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1932-1976 (Box 25)
  - Forest Grange #823 (Saginaw County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1900-1972 (Box 26)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1900-1972 (Box 45)
  - Bennington Grange #873 (Shiawassee County)
    - Secretary's record book 1943-1946 (Box 27)
  - Maple Hill Grange #691 (Antrim County)
    - Secretary's record book 1919-1924 (Box 27)
  - Saline Grange #1831 (Washtenaw County)
    - Secretary's record books 1938-1942 (Box 27)
  - Skandia Grange #1410 (Marquette County)
    - Secretary's record books 1909-1917, 1954-1959 (Box 27)
  - Crawford Grange #934 (Crawford County)
    - Secretary's record books and membership roll 1952-1966 (Box 27)
  - Four Towns Grange #745 (Lenawee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1900-1903, 1959-1970 (Box 27)
  - Weston Grange #276 (Lenawee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1874-1879, 1881-1883 (Box 27)
  - Fruit Ridge Grange #276 (Lenawee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1943-1949 (Box 27)
  - South Arm Grange #815 (Charlevoix County)
    - Secretary's record books 1900-1902, 1950-1954 (Box 27)
  - South Dover Grange #720 (Lenawee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1900-1904, 1963-1967 (Box 27)
  - Woodstock Grange #438 (Lenawee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1903-1930, 1964-1973 (Box 27)
  - Geneva Grange #1227 (Midland County)
    - Secretary's record book 1948-1950 (Box 27)
  - Macomb County Pomona Grange #32
    - Booklet containing reports of activities and programs (Box 27)
  - Maple Grove Grange #1255 (Charlevoix County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1905-1986 (Box 28)
  - Medina Grange #277 (Lenawee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1947-1952, 1956-1965 (Box 28)
  - Marion Center #956 (Charlevoix County)
    - Secretary's record books 1902-1905, 1957-1958 (Box 28)
  - Rock Elm Grange #705 (Charlevoix County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1895-1952 (Box 29)
  - Coleman Grange #1226 (Midland County)
    - Secretary's record books 1930-1934, 1945-1948 (Box 29)
  - Ponto Grange #1262 (Saginaw County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1905-1977 (Box 30)
      (also records of juvenile grange #156)
  - Lapeer Grange #246
    - Secretary's record book 1942-1947, 1949-1953 (Box 31)
  - Cambria Grange #74 (Hillsdale County)
    - Secretary's record books 1938-1947 (Box 31)
  - Ironwood Grange #1800 (Gogebic County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1916-1933, 1947-1954 (Box 31)
  - Unionville Grange #1636 (Tuscola County)
    - Secretary's record books 1949-1968 (Box 31)
  - Millington Grange #755 (Tuscola County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1912-1962 (Box 31)
  - Goodrich Grange #887 (Genesee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1901-1904, 1949-1954 (Box 31)
  - Burton Center Grange #1072 (Genesee County)
    - Secretary's record book 1955-1967 (Box 31)
  - Davison Grange #1285 (Genesee County)
    - Secretary's record books 1903-1909, 1941-1946, 1963-1974 (Box 31)
  - Harbor Springs Grange #730 (Emmet County)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings and photographs, 1993-1994 (Box 31)
  - Rose Township Grange #1826 (Oakland County)
    - Minute book November 1953- (Box 31)
  - North Sylvan Grange #1460 (Washtenaw County)
    - Minutes 1949-1964 Applications for membership (Box 31)
  - Lakeview Grange #872 (Otsego County)
    - Applications for membership (Box 31)
  - Devereaux Grange #45 (Jackson County)
    (formerly Springport Grange)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1874-1988 (Box 32)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1874-1988 (cont.) (Box 33)
  - Lakeview Juvenile Grange #148 (Otsego County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1936-1954 (Box 33)
  - Forest Lawn Grange #1720 (Tuscola County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1926-1962 (Box 33)
  - Marquette County Pomona Grange #77
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1910-1943 (Box 33)
  - Ash Center Grange #471 (Monroe County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1952-1980 (Box 33)
  - Ann Arbor Grange #1566 (Washtenaw County)
    - Minute books 1937-1944, 1951-1958 (Box 34)
    - Membership material (Box 34)
  - Birthday Grange #1352 (Schoolcraft County)
    - Minute books 1922-1941, 1963-1967 (Box 34)
  - Faith Grange #594 (Sanilac County)
    - Minute books 1909-1939, 1954-1965 (Box 34)
  - Lakefield Grange #1764 (Saginaw County)
    - Minute book 1933-1944 (Box 34)
  - Saginaw Grange #770
    - Minute book 1954-1965 (Box 34)
  - Grant-Eckland Grange #1724 (Tuscola County)
    - Minute books 1927-1942, 1952-1958 (Box 34)
  - Ellington Grange #1650 (Tuscola County)
    - Minute book 1956-1958 (Box 34)
  - East Almer Grange #1701 (Tuscola County)
    - Minute books 1923-1937, 1951-1960 (Box 34)
  - Studley Junior Grange #321 (Midland County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1975-1978 (Box 34)
  - Iosco County Pomona #89
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1916-1967 (Box 34)
  - Resort Grange #841 (Emmet County)
    - Minutes 1921-1960 (Box 35)
    - Dues account books 1900-1978 (scattered) (Box 35)
    - Applications for membership (Box 35)
  - Lafayette Grange #92 (Washtenaw County)
    - Dues account books 1920-1934 (Box 35)
    - Minutes 1955-1963 (Box 35)
  - Bear Creek Grange #1266 (Emmet County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, membership materials 1905-1939, 1960-1973 (Box 37)
  - Pittsfield Union Grange #882 (Washtenaw County)
    - Minutes 1905-1987 (some gaps) (Box 38)
    - Roll books, treasurer's records 1901-1972 (Box 39)
  - Webster Grange #1111 (Washtenaw County)
    - Minutes and treasurer's records 1903-1971 (scattered) (Box 39)
  - Scio Grange #329 (Washtenaw County)
    - Minutes 1934-1964 (Box 40)
    - Membership dues 1918-1965 (Box 40)
  - Washtenaw-Wayne Pomona Grange #7
    (formerly Washtenaw Pomona Grange #7)
    - By-laws (Box 41)
    - Minutes 1911-1995 (Box 41)
    - Treasurer's records 1909-1988 (scattered dates) (Box 41)
    - Dues accounts (Box 41)
  - Austin Grange #1331 (Hillsdale County)
    - Minutes and treasurer's records 1908-1973 (Box 49)
    - Minutes and treasurer's records 1908-1973 (Box 50)
  - Hayes Grange #871 (Otsego County)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, and other reports and miscellanea 1907-2001 (Box 51)
    - Minutes, treasurer's records, and other reports and miscellanea 1907-2001 (Box 52)
- Financial records
  - Ledger 1908-1948 (Box 42)
  - Cash book 1914-1919 (Box 42)
  - Financial statements
    (see also statements throughout the minute books)
    - 1939-1953 (scattered) (Box 42)
    - 1969-1972 (Box 42)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 42)
  - Treasurer's book October 1948-September 1956 (Box 53)
  - Secretary's daybook
    - October 1945-July 1947 (Box 53)
    - August 1947-December 1949 (Box 53)
    - January 1950-October 1952 (Box 53)
- William J. Brake papers
  (W. J. Brake was state grange master and National Grange lecturer)
  - Publication: Pomona Lecturer's Bulletin 1964-1974 (Box 46)
  - Publication: Grange Lecturer's Bulletin (with handbook) 1964-1974 (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous lecture materials, correspondence, newsletters (including some earlier materials)
- Photographs
  - Earlier photos, pre-1930
    (item description)
    - Group photo of the delegates to the state convention of the state Grange on the steps of the state capitol, Lansing, Mich. December 1878 (Folder 1)
    - Group photo of the officers of the state Grange on the steps of the state capitol, Lansing, Mich. December 1878
    - Exhibit of the Onsted Grange no. 279
    - Laborers on roof of newly constructed barn, close by remnants of demolished structure
    - Portrait of unidentified woman
  - Earlier photos, pre-1930, 1 folder
    - Officers and ex-officers of Michigan State Grange 1893 (Box 54)
    - Group photo of the 30th annual session of the Michigan State Grange December 1902, 2 copies (Box 54)
    - Car and passengers with patriotic bunting and banner reading "Charlotte P of H 1914", 2 different images (Box 54)
    - Grange Merchants Days, Adrian, Mich. showing people in the street outside of downtown stores October 1931 (Box 54)
    - Fremont Grange Hall circa 1900 (Box 54)
    - Group photo of officers circa 1920s (Box 54)